If you could be God for one week, what would you do?
Bruce Almighty is a fantasy, comedy film directed by Tom Shadyac.
Bruce Nolan toils as a "human interest" television reporter in Buffalo, NY, but despite his
high ratings and the love of his beautiful girlfriend, Bruce remains unfulfilled.
At the end of the worst day in his life, he angrily ridicules God — and the
Almighty responds, endowing Bruce with all of His divine powers.
Bruce Nolan, played by Jim Carrey.
God, played by Morgan Freeman.
Grace Connelly, played by Jennifer Aniston.
Jack Baylor, played by Philip Baker Hall.
Susan Ortega, played by Catherine Bell.
Debbie, played by Lisa Ann Walter.
Bruce Almighty is a 2003 American fantasy comedy film starring Jim Carrey.
The film follows Bruce Nolan, a down-on-his-luck television reporter who complains to God (played by Morgan Freeman)
that he is not doing his job correctly and is offered the chance to try being God himself for one week.
The film was directed by Tom Shadyac and written by Steve
Koren, Mark O'Keefe and Steve Oedekerk.
Jennifer Aniston, Steve Carell, Philip Baker Hall and Catherine Bell also star.
The film is Shadyac and Carrey's third collaboration, after Ace
Ventura: Pet Detective (1994) and Liar Liar (1997).
When released in American theaters on May 23, 2003 by Universal Pictures, Bruce Almighty received mixed reviews from critics but
was a box-office success and grossed $86.4 million in its opening weekend, a Memorial Day record at the time.
The film surprised the industry's pundits when it beat
The Matrix Reloaded the following weekend.
It went on to gross $484 million worldwide, becoming the fifth-highest-grossing
film of 2003 and Universal 4th highest grossing film when released.
Evan Almighty — a spin-off sequel focusing on Steve Carell's character, with Shadyac and Oedekerk returning to
direct and write, respectively, and Freeman also reprising his role — was released on June 22, 2007.
In addition, three Indian remakes of the film - Krishnarjuna (Telugu-speaking), Arai En 305-il
Kadavul (Tamil-speaking), and God Tussi Great Ho (Hindi-speaking) - were released in 2008.
The film explores themes of new love, lovesickness, moon, street gang, moses.
The tone is lighthearted.